Guide to the Norton Canfield Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Norton Canfield papers
1933-1974
MS 1293
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
14.25
(14 boxes)
Personal papers and research notes of Norton Canfield relating to audiology. Included are papers documenting a national hearing survey, a Connecticut hearing survey, various New Haven, Connecticut projects, and an Army hearing center.
Canfield, Norton, 1903-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Yale University Historical Medical Library, 1980; and gift of Norton Canfield, 1984.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research. The operating notes may contain protected medical information and are closed until processed.
Biographical / Historical
Norton Canfield: physician; B.S., Dartmouth, 1925; M.D., University of Michigan, 1929; instructor, University of Michigan, 1929; instructor, University of Michigan Hospital, 1930-1933; instructor, Yale Medical School, 1933-1935, assistant professor, 1935-1938, associate professor and Chief of Otolaryngology, 1938-1951, associate clinical professor, 1951-1962; Chief of Otolaryngology and founding director of the Virgin Island Hearing and Speech Center, 1962-1973; private practice,1974-
Scope and Contents
Personal papers and research notes of Norton Canfield relating to audiology. Included are papers documenting a national hearing survey, a Connecticut hearing survey, various New Haven, Connecticut projects, and an Army hearing center.
Audiology; Medicine; Physicians; Canfield, Norton, 1903-
- Inventory
  - Collected papers and New Haven projects (Box 1)
  - Collected papers and New Haven projects (Box 2)
  - National Hearing Survey and Connecticut Hearing Survey (Box 3)
  - National Hearing Survey and Connecticut Hearing Survey (Box 4)
  - Army papers and Army hearing centers (Box 5)
  - Army papers and Army hearing centers (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
  - Canfield operating notes, 1930s-1940s (Box 9)
    Conditions Governing Access
    May contain protected medical information and is closed until processed.
  - Slides (Box 9A–9C)
    Scope and Contents
    Slides may have been produced by or in collaboration with Walter Hughson as part of his clinical case files.
  - Unknown (Box 10)
- Additional Material, Accession 1985-M-005
  - Correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 11)
  - Audiology, 1949-1970 (Box 11)
  - Hearing – A Handbook, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Holmgren, Gunnar, 1937-1952 (Box 11)
  - Hughson, Walter, 1935-1944 (Box 11)
  - Mexico
    - Instituto Nacional de la Comunicacion Humana: seminars, 1973 (Box 11)
    - Medical practice, 1971-1974 (Box 11)
    - University of Mexico, 1972-1974 (Box 11)
  - National Hearing Council, 1948 (Box 11)
  - Oughterson, A.S.: obituary, 1956 (Box 11)
  - U.S. Veterans Administration: consultant, 1948-1960 (Box 11)
  - Virgin Islands Hearing and Speech Center, 1963-1973 (Box 11)